Depth, first search or depth, first traversal algorithm, the FSS is a recursive algorithm for searching
all the vertices of a graph or tree data structure.
Traversal means visiting all the nodes of a graph a standard DFS implementations, but each vertex of
the graph and to do categories they're visited and none visited or the stack.
The purpose of the algorithm is to mark each vertex as visited while avoiding cycles.
This is that very important note that you should understand when using the DFS.
The purpose of the algorithm is to mark each vertex as visited while avoiding that cycle.
That the algorithm work as follows start by putting one by one, by putting anyone of that gravitas
on the top of the stack.
But you should consider that numerical order, the alphabetical order, ascending, descending or whatever
you want.
So as that question dictates or as the situation dictates, if you are dealing with ascending or descending,
whether in alphabetical or numerical order, you should consider and detect the start of the graph.
Take that top item of the stack and add it to their visited list.
Create a list of that vertex adjacent nodes and add the new ones which are not.
Visit the list to the top of the stack.
Keep repeating these previous steps until the stack is empty.
Let's take an example here, and we start from zero.
Here how the depth first search algorithm works with an example we use unhear direct to the graph.
So we start from Vertex Zero that the FC algorithm starts by putting it into the visited list and putting
all the adjacent vertices in that stack.
What are the adjacent adjacent vertices of this vertex?
Zero.
If we start from zero, we follow it.
We reach one.
One will give us to do will give us three.
Three will give us zero again.
OK, so we start by the visited nodes from zero.
We go one two and the three.
We have visited these four nodes starting from zero.
So what is the last element that we have reached?
We have reached three, so we put at the stack three.
OK?
Till now, it's very simple.
We follow this order.
We have reached zero again.
OK.
No.
This a visit that note we have started from zero.
If we start again from zero, we don't go to any, you know, so we have finished the year we move to
one one will give us two and to give us three of three will give us zero, zero will give us one.
So we have done we just want nonunion.
No, no new nodes will be visited by using one.
If we go to do here, two will give us a new node because we have visitor three.
We are not going to visit that gate.
We visit two, we visit for four, will give us five.
Five will give us six.
Six will give us seven and seven.
No new notes will be given.
OK, so what are the visited notes that we have visited?
Starting from two we have started from?
Here from four, five, six and seven, these are the visited notes that we have started from through.
OK, what is their last note that we have reached?
Starting from do we have reached the last element, which is seven cell.
We add seven to their stack.
It's very simple algorithm.
OK, you understand it, OK?
Since the visited notes have been reached and reached, the maximum and all the nodes have been have
been visited correctly.
Like this six and seven?
We start from there from the last note that it is on the stack, so.
If we go from seven.
Back.
What is the last note that we will reach?
We will reach six, so we add to the stack.
Six.
If we go back, what is the note that we will reach?
We were each five, so we had five to the stack.
If we go back from five, what is the note that we were at each?
We were reached for four.
We will reach.
What is the note that we will reach, we will reach to so thought we were reach for a two?
Okay, it's very simple.
Two three is in the stack.
We will not go from here.
We will go from here.
OK, so we don't go through to the three, we go to the one.
So the previous note is what?
What is the last note before previous to the one, which is zero?
So we have added the visited notes, all vertices, we have visited them and the stack we have added
them in this order.
Three seven six five four two one zero.
OK.
This is that depth first algorithm in undirected graph.
Authority director Degraffe, the undirected graph is much simpler.
OK.
We will deal with the next video, so we'll take a look at an example.
We call we will code in C and Java the DFS, but we will use that undirected.
So the depth first search algorithm, why we use like this, why we are learning like this application
of DFS algorithm for finding the path.
The test, if the graph is bipartite for finding the strongly connected components of a graph or for
detecting the cycles in the graph, if we consider this graph, what is the strongly connected points?
We have four, zero, one, two and three.
This is the first one.
This is the strongly connected components.
Four, five six.
And we have the last one is seven, and we have learned this in the previous videos in the strongly
connected components of a graph and for detecting the cycles in the graph.
This is prohibited in many things, in many coding trials and many coding situations.
So we just need to detect that cycles and a graph and to prevent them.
So we use that depths for.